# WILLIAM CONNATSER

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

EMAIL: me@williamconnatser.com
PORTFOLIO: williamconnatser.com
GITHUB: github.com/WilliamConnatser
LINKEDIN: linkedin.com/in/WilliamConnatser

#### **SUMMARY**

Hard-working Software Engineer who has been fascinated with technology since the pre-teen years. Channeling that natural interest and curiosity into a profession fuels my daily growth and ambition. Possesses a strong attention to detail, and the ability to work independently with little supervision.

#### **PROJECTS**

3/2021 <u>npmjs.com/package/pg-toolbox</u> **PG Toolbox** 

Spare time solo project

Node.JS | PostgreSQL | Mocha | Babel

- Suite of CLI utility scripts which assists programmers manage Postgres databases
- Promotes writing pure SQL instead of using knex or an ORM for learning purposes github.com/WilliamConnatser/pg-toolbox

#### 9/2020 <u>AdamsMansionRetreats.com</u> **Adams Mansion**

One month solo project

NextJS | Serverless Functions | PostgreSQL

- Marketing and informational website with calendar functionality and an admin panel to keep track of availability and bookings
- Integrated with SendGrid API to send auto-generated emails when the user submits the Contact Us form and the Booking form

# 5/2019 <u>ChallengeJS.com</u> ChallengeJS

One month group project

React | Express | PostgreSQL | Auth0

- JavaScript coding challenge application
- Worked on all aspects of the stack
- Leveraged web workers to run arbitrary code client-side and run tests aithub.com/labs13-clone

# **4/2019** <u>stocklylandingpage.netlify.app</u> **Stockly**

One week group project
React | Express | PostgreSQL

- Leverages sentiment analysis to predict stock prices and view market data
- Solely responsible for the entire back-end
- Architected data caching to get around API limit restrictions <u>github.com/lambda-stockly</u>

#### **SKILLS**

### Languages

HTML | CSS | Sass | LESS JavaScript | Node.JS | Python

#### Front-end Frameworks

React I Vue

#### **Back-end Frameworks**

Express | NextJS | Apollo GraphQL Django | Flask

#### **Databases**

Microsoft SQL | PostgreSQL | SQLite MongoDB

### **Operations Management**

Git | Linux | Docker | Kubernetes | Jenkins Let's Encrypt | PM2 | Nginx | SSH | VPS Netlify | Heroku | ZEIT

#### **Computer Science**

Data Structures | Algorithms | OOP

#### **EDUCATION**

## 02/2019 to 12/2019 Lambda School

Full Stack Web Development

- Procured extensive experience building full-stack web applications, learning computer science fundamentals, and working with team workflows

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# 8/2020 to Present Florida Blue

Jacksonville, FL

Associate IT Developer

- Promoted from a contractor at Pro Unlimited LLC to an employee in August of 2020 with similar responsibilities & job duties
- Architected and developed a fullstack reporting application which assisted managers' day-to-day duties by generating reports efficiently and accurately

### 1/2020 to 8/2020 Pro Unlimited LLC

Jacksonville, FL

Associate Software Developer

- Worked with multiple associates on several projects simultaneously while maintaining solid communication across teams and consistently meeting deadlines
- Significantly contributed to enhancements and bug fixes on numerous fullstack JavaScript and Node.js applications which made business processes more efficient

# 1/2018 to 7/2019

# WEC Land Services College Station, TX

Software Engineer / Title Examiner

- Architected a web application which organized a large ranch's legal documents by integrating with a FTPaaS API
- Performed meticulous oil & gas title research to determine surface, mineral and royalty ownership of property